JONATHAN PAPIR

papir805@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

A seasoned mathematician who can communicate complex ideas to technical and non-technical people alike. Looking to transition into data analytics by leveraging a passion for solving problems and a high level of comfort with statistical concepts. Devoting three years of free time to courses and self-learning has enabled me to become well versed in the technical aspects of the field and produce personal projects demonstrating aptitude. Please look at my portfolio to see what I'm capable of doing.

EXPERIENCE

SEPT 2016 - PRESENT: MATH TEACHER, FUSION ACADEMY - LOS GATOS, CA

- Instructs students in a one-on-one learning environment focusing on developing strong quantitative analysis skills.
- Delivers content to non-technical audiences that relate difficult ideas in a clear and easy to understand manner.
- Pioneered the use of iPad technology in the classroom and lead the transition to its adoption by the entire math department.
- Produced over fifty testing and homework resources that are used by the math department.
- Praised in every yearly review as having excellent (highest rating given) content knowledge.
- Recognized in over 90% of quarterly reviews for delivering high-level lessons that are concise and easy to digest.
- Manage resources and grading for 16 courses every semester in Canvas' learning management system.
- Utilize Salesforce to access student data and tailor lessons plans on an individualized level.
- Oversee multiple long-term projects on migration or recreation of class resources from one learning management system to another.

SEPT 2011 - SEPT 2016: REPORTING ANALYST/DISPATCHER, UNDERGROUND COMMUNICATIONS - SAN JOSE, CA

- Wrote hundreds of reports in Microsoft Excel summarizing property damage in over 30 regions and distributed to stakeholders.
- Maintained the lowest error rate among all ten employees in the company.
- Conducted weekly and monthly ad hoc reporting requests for clients.
- Simultaneously monitored radio and computer aided display systems of over 40 fire departments for reports of fire/flood damage.
- Dispatched between 2-10 fire/flood chasers to the scene of a lead upon confirmation of property damage.
- Researched and summarized information from public and private databases for thousands of leads regarding property damage.
- Wrote a script that restarted listening stations automatically, reducing the rate of missed leads by over 10% per month.

MAY 2007 - JUNE 2008: COMPUTER CONTRACTOR, FUSE INTEGRATED MARKETING SYSTEMS - WALNUT CREEK, CA

- Oversaw organization and data input for two client databases.
- Performed maintenance and upgrades of local network consisting of five computer workstations.
- Gathered requirements from clients regarding creating new or improving existing marketing materials.
- Designed business development marketing materials using Adobe InDesign.
- Edited hundreds of marketing photos during post-production using Adobe Photoshop.
- Responsible for introducing a local file server, which improved organization and access to client marketing materials.

MAY 2006 - PRESENT: PRIVATE TUTORING, SELF-EMPLOYED- SAN JOSE, CA

- Provided support for hundreds of students with emphasis on improving problem solving skills.
- Nurtured relationships with families to facilitate educational growth and student satisfaction.
- Hundreds of satisfied families consistently emphasizing their children's renewed interest in math.

PROJECTS

REDDIT ACCOUNTING EXPLORATORY DATA ANALYSIS

- Using Python, survey data from Reddit was cleaned and visualized to explore relationships between salary and other factors.
- The two factors contributing most to annual salary were identified and regression models were built to quantify these relationships.
- During the analysis, evidence of a pay gap among genders emerged, and is explored further in this <u>Tableau story</u>.

CRAIGSLIST (CL) WEB SCRAPER

- A Python tool to scrape CL postings and store the results in PostgreSQL to curate a dataset on competing math tutoring prices.
- Duplicate postings were identified with word vectorization and then removed to ensure only prices for unique tutors remained.
- Using <u>Tableau</u> to compare prices across geographic segments, it was determined that my rates could be increased by almost 25% and still remain competitive.

TELEVISION (TV) AD CAMPAIGN REPORT

- A Python data pipeline that automates cleaning ad data from Excel files, calculating key metrics, and generating summary reports.
- One report's results are summarized in a PowerPoint presentation detailing which TV networks are most cost-efficient for ad spend.

SCHOLARLY ARTICLE ANALYSIS

• Using data from a scholarly article, A/B testing, confidence interval analysis, and linear regression modeling was performed to understand acupuncture treatments and their effect on hypertension.

POKÉMON LEGENDARY K-NEAREST NEIGHBOR AND LOGISTIC CLASSIFIERS

- Models built to predict whether a Pokémon is legendary, trained on generation 1-6 data, which had heavily imbalanced class sizes.
- Imbalanced class sizes made training difficult as a naïve model could achieve 92% accuracy by always guessing non-legendary.
- Using over and under-sampling techniques during training resulted in models that were able to generalize better, achieving 92-94% accuracy on testing data from generations 7-8 (82% non-legendary), indicating the model could distinguish reasonably well.

SQL QUERIES

- Queries written in MySQL and PostgreSQL, which include documentation of all logic.
- Queries perform common business tasks utilizing joins, window functions, subqueries, common table expressions, and more.

R TO PYTHON

- A project to port R code from recently released chapters of the textbook *Introduction to Statistical Learning* to Python.
- Code from labs on neural networks, survival analysis, and regression is reproduced as closely as possible.

EDUCATION

B.S. BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS: SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY

COURSES/CERTIFICATIONS

PYTHON BASIC - CERTIFICATION, HACKERRANK, OCTOBER 2022

SQL INTERMEDIATE - CERTIFICATION, HACKERRANK, MARCH 2022

THE ULTIMATE MYSQL BOOTCAMP: GO FROM SQL BEGINNER TO EXPERT - CERTIFICATION, UDEMY, JAN 2021

CIS 107 - DATA SCIENCE, SAN JOSE CITY COLLEGE, DEC 2020

CIT 134A - PROGRAMMING IN PYTHON, EVERGREEN VALLEY COLLEGE, MAY 2020

INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTATIONAL THINKING AND DATA SCIENCE - CERTIFICATION, EDX, MAY 2020

INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER SCIENCE AND PROGRAMMING USING PYTHON - CERTIFICATION, EDX, FEB 2020

LEARNING PYTHON FOR DATA ANALYSIS AND VISUALIZATION - CERTIFICATION, UDEMY, DEC 2019